谨以此片追忆逝去的童年，如果你也有这样的童年的话欢迎加入我们的贴吧"神剑传奇"。本作品之片源来自互联网，版权归原公司所有。任何组织和个人不得公开传播或用于任何商业盈利用途，一切后果由该组织或个人承担！制作者不承担任何法律及连带责任！请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
FRance 2. Ecipsc Animaz ion, Tooncan PRoductions Xll Ine
传司
Tooncan productions xIl Ine
FRance 2, Ecipse Animaz ion, Tooncan PRoductions Xll Inc
翻译：英语辅导频道
输入/时间轴/压制：harry159821/黑月
F
2.∈
SCRipt by
ChRistophe pujol and Thomas FoRwood
校对：
MatrIx
Maur?
aurlx
莫里克斯
Matrix!
里克川
Mannl
Mault
Mauley
Maull
莫里
Maulex
Mannix
Who's there?
谁在那
Hello?
有人吗
A Shogi?
去师吗
See anything yet. wip?
发现什么没威普
第？集
Not even a shadow of a
Shogi anywhere on the horizon
限望到地平线都没有任何法师的影气
This is the last place
生命老显尔里克斯到过的地
where/the Book of-Life
shows any trace of Mauri
ts like he just
dropped off the page
好象他就此失踪
The Book doesnt just
lose track of someone like th
生命之书来没有象那样跟去过谁
especially a Shog
其对象还是个法市
omething omust
have happened to him
肯定发生什么事
Something?
发生什么事可
生什么事了
Something 2
%出了我长
PlyOS wazo Dpag SB epdluugs
e DuyRewoe e闻pD
Could it be something as
simple as being frozen solid?
能有被冻住了那么简单吗
/
f
Maybe he's covered in snow!
也许他被雪盖住了
Look! Footprints
看有脚印
有多
Look Footer
Hel probably. tried to
reach the volcano over there.
他可能想经这前徒火
Hey. lsn't this the
volcano with the ice fortress?
嘿不是冰厮密的火山吗
That Shogi monastery r
那座三基隐
el they hid
Kwodahn's terrible weapons?
原不是藏着科沃达那供可械脑掌髀
We destroyed-the weapon
我们把那件武器销毁了
but the monastery's
still st
ig. wip
可寺院依旧稳稳耸立在那里威普
Let's not waste any timer
我们环要浪费时间
Hey! Wab a minute!
等一下
I鹆一下
Dont you realize
cursed
你们不觉得那座冰堡被下咒了吗
句始斗制业(
pesos
ezieer now 1.间
Donit you realize
that fortress is cursed?
你们不觉得那座冰堡被下咒了吗
You can wait for us
here./ if you like, Wipl
想你可以在这里等们威警
Look he dropped something.
看他下东西了
That's strange.
真奇怪
It looks like a button\
from a Shogi habit
象是法师服上的纽扣
but the engraved crystal on it
isnt the usual shape or colour
可上面浏的水品其形状和额色都不导常
Let's see what the
Book of Life says about it
我看生命之书写了些什么
A
anything wrong
是不是有么问题
don' t know
我不知道
aIt's as if the Book of
Life just repelled the button.
好象生命之书很制这个子
Just like this
mountain is repelling me
就象我思座邮一藏也不
that anybody cares
闻爱人美心个
Hey!
iAeH
Morgan?
是刚吗
I wish yyou Shogis
woutd)knock of something
称们邀些师下次
咄现的假温下
wisl out Sharts
但感你们装师产
出现的明假温一下
Herik! Another of our
brothersooo has disappeared
哈里宽又有一个见弟失踪了
Connection is weakoo
going to Mallory
盛应立变霸了侠来吗里
eW-oi upon
oaoyeam s! uopoeuuo○
Connection is weake
going to Mallory.o
盛应变的了来吗
looo Be carefulono Herik
我。你们要小心哈里克
Morgan!
莫刚
What's happening Herik
了哈里克
Something is interfering
with our telepathic connection
有什么在干拢我们传心感应
don'tlike this
不喜欢这样
You should meet
Morgan at -Mallory Herik!
哈里你最好去超吗洛里见下类刚
I think
我也这么认
but what about Mauri?
可莫里听温么办
cant just give up the search
我不能就此放弃搜寻
Dont Morty
Don't worry
别担心
You\go to Mallory
你去洛里
Mand we'll keep, looking for
Maurix at the ice fortress
我们会继续在冰堡寻莫里克斯
By. we, you mean you
and Princess Diana, right?
你说的我们是指你利娜公主
an you
Djamaa tigi
说的哦打爨脂你御窈吧
By: we, you mean you
and Princess Djana, right?
说的我们是缩你和老游公
的我幻是腊你制履裙虚
By weo you mean you
and Pudtroeess Djamal right
你说的我你潮娜公主唧
you lean you
你说的你制公塞思
By we, you mean you
and Princess Djana, rightp
你说的我们是猎你娜公主吧
imea
W画esa
tosend Lerik off alkomeoon tight
我是诞嗡黑览单驰前费不密金对嗯
meanor a wondkdnit be gaft
是解孤场宽单独前悲不露测嗯
mean,it wou t be saf
to send Herik off alone. right?
我是说让哈里克单重前去不安全对
You do
you wa
你想怎么做就怎么做吧成普
ou do what you want, Wipe
你想狐涿做就做t
截们吧
ets go
Just as homey as ever
切都是那么自然
remember right
如果我没记错
there s a chute that leads
to the for tress just ahead
有条斜槽直递冰堡
Heelis
在
H
这
You ready?
准备好了
The Ice Fortress!
ever thought
I'd ever see it again
我从没想过会再见到它
agree with W
我同戒普的说
I never wanted
see it again
我以来就不想见到官
Mauri! Hello?
莫里克斯你在
If Mauri is in there
eard th
要是莫里克斯在他肯定听到了
and so did anyone
who might be with him
而目可能有人和他一起
You think Maur ix might
have been takem prisoner?
你认为莫里克期有能被抓了鸣
Im just saying it's possible
我只是说有可能
and we should be more careful
Hear that?
到了吗
Look out!
小
小心
Look our
That snowball
didn't fall by itselfi
那个雪球不是自己掉下来的
Somebody's trying to keep us out!
有人想把我们赶出去
Yeah, hardly a warm welcome!
没错多热烈的欢迎仪式啊
图
don'tlike this quiet
我一点都不喜欢这种死静的感觉
Silkar's tave
塞尔的酒馆
Let's hope Morgan
waiting for us insid
但愿莫刚在里面等我们
Herik
哈里克
Oh, him again
噢又是他
The last one was seen
here just two hours ago
最后一个失踪的两个小时前在这出现过
Any sign of Mauri×?
找到莫里克斯的踪迹了吗
Only his tracks in the snow
只在雪上发现了他的脚印
But we did find this
不过我们发现了这个
But it looks like
it belonged to a Shog
不过看起来是法师的所有物一
Do you recognize it
你以识这个东西吗
Yes now I remember
的现在我想起来了
是的现在我想起来了
Yes. nowalp-remember
是的在我想起来
It was on the cover of an old
volume in the monastery library:
三基寺书库里一本古老宗卷
的封面上有这
the very one that
Mauri came to consul
莫里克斯经常查阅那本
So it's back to
the Shogi island
那我们要回三基寺岛一趟了
I need to see that book
我得看看那本书
NA
w/
差加写
Hey! Who's there?
嘿谁在那
Land in sight!
看到陆地了
Hello?
有在吗
Anyone here? Hello!
有人在
There isn't anybody
here anymore
已经没人了我感觉得到
Oh no, here we go again
哦不要
It's clear- now
现在事情很楚了
Someone, or something
is hunting shog
有人或有什么东西正在猎捕法师
And am the last
fied Shogi on the list
而我是他们的最后目标吧
Right. Let's get
he library then
错我们去书库吧
and have a look at Maurix's book
未看看莫里克斯查阅过的那本书
L
Look out
s
Tara. look at this symbol
塔拉看这个符号
sn't it the same as
the one on the button?
这不是跟纽扣上的图案一样卩
same as
Smit it
saunas
这不是限动打的察一半料
-means
惠呢
naNsen
ee出一
Yes but what does it mean?
对可这代表什么意思
It looks like a group of shogis
worshipping something, or someone
象是群法师在频拜什么东西或者什么
But thats
d
可是
价
odd
可是很奇怪
飞
cont
bow down Before anyone.
法师以来不对谁的
logIs
anone
不对的
he shogissdon
anyone
低
ow dowasbefore anyone
The shogis don'l
befor
师从谁
ow (down before anyon
emblem of the
这量外品的
This is the emblem of the
Order of the Black Crystal
这是黑水晶一族的徽章
ring any bells?
想起来了没
Never heard of it
从来没听说过
They were Shogis, just like us,
他们也是法师一就我们这样
but the Shogi Master expelled
them-for using the black crystal
但是因为他们使用黑水晶
大法师把他们驱逐了
Expelled them?
驱逐了他们
I've never heard of any
Shogis being expelled, ever.
我从没听说过有哪位法师被驱逐
Does it say why this
Black Crystal was forbidden?
上面有说为什么禁止使用黑水晶
Or what happened to it?
或者黑水晶如何了吗
Yes and no
说了一点
The Black Crystal
amplifies telepathic power,
黑水晶能够增强传心术法力
but warps the mind in the proces
但是会在这过程中迷失心智
can't find
anything about its fate
我没有找到哪有表述它命运如何
can' t believe it
难以置信
If such a dangerous crystal exists
如果真有那么危险的水晶存在
Maurix must have
wondered the same thing
有同样的想法
But why would
he go to the volcano?
要跑去火山呢
Morgan! The Ice Fortress
莫刚你说
Could that have been the home
of the Order of the Black Crystal?
冰堡有没有可能是黑水晶族的巢穴呢
It's possible
有可能
Maurix-night have
found proof of that,
莫里克斯可能找到相关的证据了
and went to find the black Crystal
然后跑去找黑水晶
That's itl Im sure of
没错我可以肯定
That's甲
Thats ait!-limm sure of
没错~可以肯定
Wip! Fly back to the Ice
Fortress and warn Djama and Tara
威普飞回冰堡提醒裘娜和塔拉」
What? You want me
o return to that place
什么你叫我飞回那个鬼地方
the fortress of ice all alone?
自己一个人回那个冰堡吗
V
We'llmeet you there
我们在那跟你碰头
But you must warn Diana
and Tara not to try any thing
可你要提醒裘娜和塔拉
<before we get there
在我们到那之前不要妄动
Sometimes I hate
knowing how to fly
有时候我真讨厌自己会
It,'s kind of creepy walking
through an abandoned fortress
走在这种荒废的冰堡中真感觉毛骨悚然
So big, so empty.
那么大那么空旷
ook out!
Maurix! Over there!
He's getting away
是莫里克斯在那边他跑了
He can only have
gone in through here
他只可能经过这里的
业
Carefull
N心点
C
ar
e、
仙点
Carefull
N心点
Careful
Either there is
amother exit or he'schidi
能还有淇他出口或者他躲起来了
Hey!
Locked from the outside
从外面锁住了
He's trapped us
他把我们困在这里
What if it wasn' t Maurix?
如果不是莫里克斯呢
It was a Shogi
Who else could it be?
是个法师难道有可能是其他人吗
Do you think Mauri wants to
revive the Order-of the Black Crystal!
你认为是不是莫里克斯
想唤醒黑水晶一族呢
Certainly not
Maurix is a good Shogi
当然不是莫里克斯是个好法师
somebody's trying
那就外有人想这么做了
and I'm sure the answer is
somewhere inside the Ice Fortress
而我走答秦就在冰堡的果个方
4 But you're itg
maybe you sh
ould stay/here
你说得对也详你应线留在这里
Whal's gongsun?
回事
An invisible force
objects!
无形的量移动物体
Only a superior
telepathic force can do this
只有拥有高阶感应法力才能做到
like the Black Crystal,s power
比如黑水晶的法力
coming to get you
是冲着你来的
Resist it, Morgan!
s trying: to
take-oMermy mind!
它想控制我的心智
lell take your place! Herik
我来代替你吧哈里克
Herik! Can you hear me
哈里克诉得到我说话吗
么
Q
出
么公
VIAN/
∥AN
物
当
了
I'mtbushed
Youre luck
Y
it tak or fl
你们
说话也不会飞
Youre lucky
说话也不会
You're lucky
Your cant talk or fly
和们真海会说话也不会
Youre lucky
你们真幸运不会说也不会
YYou canit talk or fly
你们真率运会说也不会
They cant send you
off on dangerous missions.
所以他们不会派你们去执行险的低舒
Ut takes a lot
of courage, you know!
做样的啡啦可需要勇气
A flying Shog
做会飞的师
A机h9
一做会飞的差师吗
A灿P
一位飞爱师
位会飞的法师吗
A
g shogi?
位会飞差师
啊
Something tells
me that cant be good
Now who could that be?
那会是谁啊
Easy does
p
别慌张威普
Just another of
these flying Shogis
不就是另一个会飞的法师嘛
Nice work
k
The Sword of Justice
eems to haver many uses
神剑的途坯真多啊
Now, let's find Maurix
现在我们去找莫里克斯吧
Absolutely. He's
got some explaining to do
是他得给我们个解释
Djana. did you hear that?
裘娜你听到了没
Someone's coming
有人过来了
Over there!
那边
A
二
Herik?
哈里克是你吗
He can't see or hear you, Djana
他现在看不到你也听不到你叫他裘娜
Morgan
what happened to, Herik?
莫刚哈里克怎么
He's under a telepathic spel
他中了传心咒
ve followed him here from
the monastery on the flying wing
我从三基寺坐飞船跟他过来这里的
Didn't Wip warn you?
威普没有提醒你们吗
No we haven't seen him
没有我们都没见到他啊
Quick. we mustn't lose Herik!
快点不能失去哈里克的踪影
There's Wip, and Mauri
威普在那还有莫里克斯
They're alf here
他们都在
Who could have
done this to them?
到底是谁把他们变成这样了
Shhh! Somebody's coming
u有人过来
Over there
在那里
That's the Shogi
who tried to trap us
他就是想困住我们的那位法师
Tell me what you see, Djana
裘娜把你看到的告诉我
He isn't dressed like the others
他穿得跟其他法师不一样
and he's holding a
staff topped with a crystal
手里拿着三根手杖手杖顶着一颗水晶
n the name of the Shogi
以法师的名义
open your souls to the
ight of the Black Crystal
向黑水晶之光打开你们的灵魂吧
It's giving off
an energy sphere
他发出了一个水晶球
he Order of the Black Crystal
黑水晶的召唤
Herik was right
哈里克说对了
What's
e doing
他在干什么
He's absorbing the
Shogis mental energy
在吸走法师的所有能量
到:
You are the servants
f the Black Crystal
你们都是黑水晶的仆人
你
You must obey
们必须服从黑水晶的命令
The shogi master
是大法师
The black Shogi is
trying to summon him.
黑法师想召唤他出来
That's why he needed
to assemble all the Shogis!
那就是他把所有法师都抓来的原因
To use them against their will
利用他们对抗他们自己的意志
can sense a
great telepathic struggle
我感觉到一股强大的心灵挣
The Black Crystal is pushing them
all far beyond their mental limits
黑水晶正在把他们逼到极限
Herik is still resisting
哈里克还在抵抗
4 It's. so hard
太难受了
(
Ive seen enough
我看不下去
We can t let that
madman torture them to death!
我们不能让那人把他们折磨致死
No, Tara
不行塔拉
You will only draw his attention
你这样做只会让他发现我们
and he will crush us
然后他会把我们都干掉的
e only have one weapon
which can stand up to such power.
我只有一件武器可以对抗这股力量
Xcalibur
是神剑
》
There you are, traitor
The master wants to see you!
你在那啊叛徒主人要见你
Quietly'Djana
轻点裘娜
Try=to take him before
he knows you're there
要在他发现你之前把他制用
Right, but (trst l want to see
who the master is behind that door
没错不过我想先看看那门后的主人是谁
ChOU
神剑
Xcalibur
神佥
Huh? Master?
怎么回事主人
Fr
定
Who's there?
谁在那
So much for sneaking up on him,
受够这样偷偷摸摸了
I'll go and see
what Djana is up to!
我去看看裘娜那边进行得如何
Tara! Where are you?
塔拉你在哪
neelie Wo山
Tara! Where are you?
塔拉你在哪
You traitor!
你这叛徒
Enough of this
masquerade! Who are you?
伪装够了吧你到底是谁
Look out, Djana
裘娜小心
He can be at two
lace at the same time
他可以同时出现在两个不同的地方
Destroyed by his own-magic
被自己的魔力干掉了
P
M
噢
Our friends are free, Morgan
我们的朋友们自由了莫
Were free
我们得救了
I've got my
own brain back again
我终于找回自己的意识了
Thanks to xcalibur. no doubt
毫无疑问多亏了神剑
And no thanks to me
都是我的错
should never have
freed that Shogi from the ice!
我不该把那个法师从冰里解救出来
That Shogi in the Black cloak?
你是说穿着黑色斗篷的那个法师吗
He was trapped in the ice?
他被困在冰里了吗
Yes, and he would still be there
是的要是我没有在书库
发现那本古老的魔法书
if i hadnt discovered that
ld book of magic in the library
他现在还被困在冰里呢
It wasnt catalogued
or listed at all
那本书没有被归入书库目录
So I became curious
听以我很好奇
It told of the fierce
struggle between the Shogi Master
书里面描述了大法师
and the Order of the black Crystal
和黑水晶一族之间那场激烈的较量
I couldn't believe
that some of our brothers
当时我真不敢相信
had really betrayed
everything we stand for.
真有兄弟背叛了我们拥护的一切
wanted to find out the truth
我想找出事实真相
so I headed for the Ice Fortre
所以前往冰堡一探究竟
Whos there?
谁在那
Hello?
有人吗
若火
Hello?
有
In the middle of the storm
I saw a man waving at me
在暴风雪中我看到有人向我招手
lost sight of him
我失去了他的踪影
looked for him
然后跑去找他
buta‖ found
was the body of a Shogi,
可我找到的却是一具法师尸体
trapped in the ice
被埋在冰下
while his body was
preserved in the ice
而他的身体保存在冰下也完好无缺
The moment I freed him
在我把他解救出来那
I was enslaved
我就中了他的招
the man waving
at you in the storm
暴风雪里向你招手的人
could only have been an illusion
只可能是个幻象
Created by the Black Crystal
是黑水晶的杰作
don' t know
我不知道
Whoever it was
无论他是谁
The Black Crystal was
the evil source of his power
黑水晶是他邪恶法力的来源
It must be destroyed
黑水晶必须被销毁
Too late. little Shogis
太晚了小术士们
Kwodahn! No
科沃达不要
Djana! Wait!
Destroy the crystal!
裘娜等等先把水晶销毁掉
i
Now it's your turn, Kwodahn!
现在该你了科沃达
By destroying the Crystal
销毁了水晶
Without the Crystal
the Ice Fortress is falling apart
没有了水晶冰堡要坍塌了
We've got to get out of here
我们得离开这里
(
六的测
,
TE.-
和一
We're lucky to be alive, Mauri
艮幸运我们还能活着莫里克斯
after you took on the Order of
the Black Crystal and Kwodahn
是和黑水晶族以及科沃达较量过后
The great Magil
The fault is mine, my children
是我的错孩子们
and I humbly ask
for your forgiveness.
我诚地请求你彻原谅
should have taught you abou
the Order of the Black Crystal
我应该早点把黑
族的事告诉你
It's revival nearly destroyed us all
他们的复满差点段掉了一切
because I left you unprepared
因为我让你们未能提前防范
Shogi Master,
大法师
why isnt there anything
about it in the Book of Life?
为什么生命之书对他们只字未提呢
This fortress was-ance
home to my best disciples
座冰堡原本是我最优作徒炼的地方
until they were seduced=by the
terrible power of the Black- Crytal
后来他被黑水品可的的为锈入歧途
the end
Shogi fought against Shogi
到最后师大战法师
You Master?
You fought your own disciples?
大法师你跟你自己的门徒较品吗
To the last one
最后
The fate of the
world was at stake
整个世界危在
But the experience was so painful
次的经历太痛苦
that I wanted to
destroy all memory of it
所以我想把它从记忆中全部抹去
Alas,I should have known
that one cannot erase the past
该死我早该知道没谁能把过去抹掉
From now on, it will be
included in the Book of Life
现在开始这件事会被记入生命之书
Come, Maule
来吧莫动
It's time we told our brothers
the story of the Black Crysta
是时候克弟们饼谢黑水品的故事了
the whole story
讲进整个过
井讲整
the whole story
讲整个过
I
Hal! Well, I'll b
哈我也会唧
the Shogi=Master Jost
apologized to a Shogi apprerofice
法师居然向实
y the Shogi Master Just
guess that proves the
whole world's upside-down
我想那是不是证明现在整个世界倒了
No. Wip, it just proves
成只是而
No。 WLp it just proves
不威感是证明
that even the best of
us sometimes make mistak
即是我们幽申量优的人他会犯错
Now thait'sva comfort
NW。0 hatsa confortI
w
Right, well
we leave this place ASAP
哪好费建灾踪尽快离这里吧
My scales are freezing
and my stomach is rumbling
我秘侣了子也饿了
nd [um ever wrong about that!
对号那些从来不会出错的
d m ever w
网于那些我
nd [om never wrong about that
戏那些我从来不会出错的
SCRIPT SUPERTISOR
Uguru
FIECUTTYE STORY EDITOR
5cKIPT SUPCKTTSOK
KHeLA AUD
execuTIo TORT EDIToR
KECUTTYE STORY CDTOR
sislEr marathons
LNYITN5NOO 141a
5ana・著 aann otan1s
sILy
STuDIO MAKKE
.a Nurse
PRODUCTION IDMIMISTRK TOK- TOONCEH PRODUCTIONS Ill INC.
5Dn1山
PRODUCTION RDMMSTRATO是 oDEum PooucTioes l
PRODUCTION XDMINSTRXTO%- TOONCAH PRODUCTIONS IH
"
翻译：英语辅导频道
输入/时间轴/压制：harry159821/黑月
校对：